Ruoqi Tian

216 S Weinbach Ave ♦ Evansville, IN 47714 ♦ 812-618-7548 ♦ rt89@evansville.edu http://ruoqitian.com/

OBJECTIVE

Obtain full-time employment as a software engineer

SUMMARY

Over three years of programming experience; Campus leader with proven skills in leading; Record of personal and academic achievement; Works wells in teams and individually; Good communication skills

Computer Skills

Perl Ruby on Rails Javascript Foundation Git/Subversion

C/C++ SQL Java HTML/CSS Linux

EDUCATION

B.S. in Computer Science; Minor in Mathematics Expected May 2017 UNIVERSITY OF EVANSVILLE Evansville, IN Dean's List Three Terms GPA 3.43

Relevant Coursework

Object-Oriented Design Networks Operating Systems UNIX Programming Software Engineering Databases Website Design Artificial Intelligence

Projects

- Collaborated with a large corporation to design and implement Field Tech Admin, a web tool capable of solving critical problems and providing great efficiency to field workers; Utilized Perl, SQL, and AJAX; Expanded knowledge of web server structures and Foundation
- Independently coded the website for a local coffee corporation emphasizing proficiency in JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Foundation 6, and JQuery

WORK EXPERIENCE

METRONET INC Evansville, IN

MIS Intern Summer 2015-Present

- Served as a software developer on a team responsible for maintaining and improving a telecommunications billing system and integrating it with various internal and 3rd party systems for video delivery, telephony services, payment processing, scheduling, inventory management, accounting, etc.
- · Repaired all Perl scripts and eliminated bugs for existing web tools daily
- Manipulated and retrieved information from a database containing millions of subscriber records including address, phone number, services and billing information utilizing SQL

UNIVERSITY OF EVANSVILLE Evansville, IN

Supplemental Instruction Leader (C and C++)

Spring 2016

• Helped CS students with projects and homework and fielded all questions about project design

TRAYLOR BROTHERS, INC Evansville, IN

IT System Technician

Fall 2015

- Assisted supervisor in maintaining the server to ensure communication between sites located around the United States and safe transmission of sometimes confidential information
- Maintained numerous computers ensuring proper operation increasing ability to troubleshoot

CAMPUS LEADERSHIP

ASSOCIATION FOR COMPUTING MACHINERY (ACM), UE Student Chapter

Chapter Treasurer/Secretary

March 2015-Present

• Facilitated monthly chapter meetings for a group of 10 demonstrating effective leadership and interpersonal communication skills

International Orientation Leader

March 2014-Present

Mentored and introduced international students to the American campus life and cultures